AMEYA KULKARNI

CONTACT ME

+91 89568 88879

ameya.kulkarni1295@gmail.com

Pune - 411004, Maharashtra,







SUMMARY

Machine learning enthusiast with experience in working with highly complex and nonlinear data in various applications. Blockchain explorer and Python developer. Dedicated to continuous process improvement and feature engineering in the face of rapidly evolving business landscape. Proactive in addressing and resolving problems.

Full time non-conformist. Part time non-confrontationalist. Sarcastic and witty:p

SKILLS

Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Software Development Life Cycle, Technical Architecture, Team Building and Development, Agile Project Management, User Experience (UX)

Tools: R, Python, TensorFlow, Git, Bash, Scikit-Learn, SQL, MathWorks Matlab & Simulink, Web Scraping, National Instruments(NI) Multisim, Jira

Cloud: Azure, GCP, Cloudflare

OS: macOS, Windows, Unix

CERTIFICATIONS

- Improving Deep Neural
 Networks: Hyperparameter
 tuning, Regularization &
 Optimization
 Deeplearning.ai
- Machine Learning, Stanford Coursera
- O Intro to Marketing, Wharton Cousera

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Marathi, Spanish(Elementary)

WORK EXPERIENCE -

OPET PTE LTD, SINGAPORE & INDIA

Chief Technology Officer & Chief Data Scientist, November 2017 - Present

- Responsible for initial strategic business plan and product development
- Engineering an advanced database of features to build an artificial intelligence engine to drive user based recommendations
- Setting up the core machine learning department to incorporate cutting edge innovations for product improvement
- Managing a product development staff of 10 and a range of outsourced vendors
- Leading a global team spanning various departments including machine learning, blockchain, marketing, content and design across 5 geographies
- Assisting launch of Initial Coin Offering (ICO) to achieve independent rating of 4.7/5 and advanced level token economics combining artificial intelligence and blockchain for a utility token
- Part of core team to achieve angel to seed post-funding company valuation ratio of 1:10, with current valuation at \$25 million

JAMBO RIDES, UGANDA

Technical Advisor, Remote, July 2017 - Present

- Providing technical assistance for strategic product and business planning
- Scrutinizing code malfunction and did web ops
- Acting as scrum master, running a daily standup, keeping track of velocity, managing backlogs

BITS PILANI, DUBAI CAMPUS

Thesis Scholar, January 2017 - July 2017

- Researched on "Machine Learning based Mathematical Modeling for Classification of EEG Signals"
- Performed morphological operations on EEG data for modelling of epilepsy
- Introduced statistical feature extraction to reduce algorithm complexity
- Classified using Matlab Classification Learner Toolbox to simulate Support Vector Machines with an F1- score of 0.966

Head Teacher: Machine Learning, August 2016 - December 2016

- Pioneered and introduced the subject course Intro to Machine Learning under the Peer-to-Peer learning program, Placement Division, BITS Pilani, Dubai Campus
- Collaborated with a team of faculty to develop a tutorial program focused on making students placement ready
- Improved student's analytical skills by introducing state-of-the-art computer program technologies

PROJECTS -

SMART AI RECOMMENDER

October 2017 - Present

- Curated and formed data fields to optimally recommend students content based on features like their strengths, weaknesses, learning curves, study habits, preferences
- Incorporated psychometric profiling to alter conversation styles in a chatbot to personalise user experience
- Achieved 89% development accuracy and currently scaling up to same in production

MOTIVATION MAPPER

June 2016 - July 2017

- Conducted a survey on welfare facilities and its impact on employee satisfaction
- Developed a supervised learning algorithm which classified employees, based on level of motivation, by using features like salary, work timings, welfare facilities, with an accuracy of 91% in Python
- Established direct relation between employee motivation and performance and reiterated Maslow's theory of motivation using a machine learning classifier

CUSTOMER SEGMENTS

May 2017

- Classified data set using Scikit-learn's Unsupervised Learning-GMM Clustering library
- Applied Principle Component Analysis and got a silhouette score of 0.41
- Consumers segments created helped optimise supply chain management costs

EDUCATION -

UDACITY

Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree, 2017

BIRLA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY & SCIENCE, PILANI

Bachelor of Engineering (Hons.), Electronics & Communication, Al Specialisation, 2017

RIMS INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL

Cambridge International Examinations A' Levels, 2013